Guide to the Association of Professional Communications Consultants records, 1980-2017 RL.11365
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Association of Professional Communication Consultants records
1980-2017
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Association of Professional Communications Consultants
RL.11365
4 Linear Feet
The Association of Professional Communication Consultants (APCC) is an organization dedicated to educating new consultants and helping existing consultants expand and improve their businesses. The APCC records also include materials from the Association of Professional Writing Consultants (APWC), the Conference on College Composition and Communication (CCCC), and the Association of Business Communication (ABC). These entities often worked together on projects and workshops aimed at educating consultants and spreading knowledge about the profession. The collection comprises administrative materials, information about workshops, and documents belonging to former APCC President Barbara Shwom.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged in four boxes by folder in the order it was received.
Biographical / Historical
The APCC was founded in 1982 as a non-profit committed to facilitating entry into the communication consulting profession and helping existing consultants expand their businesses and improve their methods. Thus, APCC often hosted educational workshops in cities across the United States to carry out their mission. The organization frequently worked alongside organizations with similar missions, such as the Association of Professional Writing Consultants (APWC), the Conference on College Composition and Communication (CCCC), and the Association of Business Communication (ABC). There are materials from the APWC, the CCCC, and the ABC amongst the collection. The APCC was disbanded in 2014.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Provenance
The Association of Professional Communication Consultants records were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a [gift/purchase/transfer] in [year].
Collection Overview
The collection is arranged into the following 2 series: Administrative/Organizational materials and former APCC President Barbara Shwom materials. The APCC administrative and organizational materials date from 1983 to 2017 and comprise membership directories, correspondence, budgetary and financial information, meeting minutes, and workshop handouts. The Barbara Shwom materials date from the 1981 to the 2000 and comprise her personal correspondence and APWC materials.
Related Materials
Related materials can be found in the Lee Clark Johns papers at the Bingham Center.
Conference on College Composition and Communication; Business communication -- United States -- Vocational guidance; Sallie Bingham Center for Women's History and Culture
- Administrative/Organizational Materials, 1980-2017
  - Association of Professional Writing Consultants materials, 1997 (Box 1)
  - APCC new member packet, 1987-2000 (Box 1)
  - APCC manuals and booklets, 1993-1999 (Box 1)
  - APCC Website, n.d. (Box 1)
  - listserv Correspondence, 1996 (Box 1)
  - Pat McNees materials, 1990-1999 (Box 1)
  - Testimonials and stories, 2000 (Box 1)
  - Member Survey and Volunteer List, 2000 (Box 1)
  - Deciding to shut down, 2013-2014 (Box 1)
  - Fee-setting Forum, 2003 (Box 1)
  - Summer Board Retreat Nashville, TN, 1999-06 (Box 1)
  - Administrative Materials, 2001-2004 (Box 1)
  - Board and Annual Meeting Minutes Correspondence, 1996-2000 (Box 1)
  - Board and Annual Meeting Minutes, 2001-2009 (Box 1)
  - APWC/APCC Board of Directors and Annual Meeting Minutes, 1983-1997 (Box 1)
  - Quarterly Reports, 1991-1998 (Box 1)
  - Virtual Board Meeting, Summer Minutes, Quarterly Discussion Report, 1996 (Box 1)
  - CD Archive Computer Files, n.d. (Box 1)
  - APWC Annual Report + Quarterly Report, 1990-1992 (Box 1)
  - APWC Quarterly + Annual Reports, 1988-1991 (Box 1)
  - APWC Board of Directors Correspondence, 1982-1984 (Box 1)
  - APWC Incorporation and Tax, 1984-1997 (Box 1)
  - APWC Charter Membership letter + member list, 1983 (Box 1)
  - APCC Consulting Success II, 1999-2003 (Box 1)
  - APWC/APCC Newsletters, 1981-1998 (Box 1)
  - Membership Directories, 1993-1999 (Box 1)
  - Development Days/Events Materials, 1999-2001 and undated (Box 1)
  - Consulting Materials, 1987-2002 (Box 1)
  - Consulting materials, 1993 (Box 1)
  - Membership Directories, 1994-2001 (Box 1)
  - APCC History and Closing Activities, Establishing Consulting Award w/ABC, 1997-2017 (Box 3)
  - By-Laws and Articles for APWC, 1986 (Box 3)
  - APWC - Association of Professional Writing Consultants - Tax Exempt, 1984-2005 (Box 3)
  - Annual Reports and President's Messages, 2004-2010 (Box 3)
  - APCC Minutes, 1996-2011 (Box 3)
  - Budgets, 1994-2007 (Box 3)
  - Financial statements, 1997-2017 (Box 3)
  - APWC Lists of Board of Directors, 1983-2003 (Box 3)
  - APCC code of ethics, elements of professional practice, and support for federal plain language legislation, 1997-2007 (Box 3)
  - Grammar Prework, 1999-2001 (Box 3)
  - Board Activities, 1986-1988 (Box 3)
  - APWC - Programs & Projects, 1983-1989 (Box 3)
  - CCCC - Seattle Presentation APWC Business, 1988-1989 (Box 3)
  - APWC/CCCC, 1990-1991 (Box 3)
  - APWC - CCCC San Diego, 1992-1993 (Box 3)
  - APWC - Current Projects, 1993-1996 (Box 3)
  - Board Reports, 1999-2003 (Box 3)
  - Board Reports & Projects, 2003-2005 (Box 3)
  - APCC Board Retreat, 2004-2005 (Box 3)
  - Board & Retreat, 2004-2006 (Box 3)
  - APCC Board Retreat Items, 2007 (Box 3)
  - Retreat Arrangements, 2006 (Box 3)
  - APCC Board, 2009-2011 (Box 3)
  - APCC, 2013 (Box 3)
  - Web Updates, 2003-2014 (Box 3)
  - Projects dropped, 1982-1985 (Box 3)
  - Policy Manual, 2000-2005 (Box 3)
  - Correspondence regarding Position Descriptions, 2005 (Box 3)
  - APWC Membership Mailings, 1995-2002 (Box 3)
  - APWC Responses pt. 1, 1995-1997 (Box 3)
  - APWC Responses pt. 2, 1989-1995 (Box 3)
  - APWC, APCC Directories, 1987-1996 (Box 3)
  - APCC Directories, 1996-2003 (Box 3)
  - CCCC, 1980-1982 (Box 3)
  - CCCC, 1983-1984 (Box 3)
  - Teaching in Corporate Settings - 1984 CCCC Workshop, 1982-1984 (Box 3)
  - CCCC Minneapolis, APWC - Workshop on Consulting, 1983-1985 (Box 3)
  - CCCC Think Tank, 1985-1987 (Box 3)
  - APWC/CCCC Program, 1984-1989 (Box 3)
  - CCCC/APWC, 1989-1990 (Box 3)
  - ABC/APCC Chicago, 1996 (Box 3)
  - APCC/ABC Washington DC, 1996-1997 (Box 3)
  - ABC/APCC Consultants Workshop Planning Notes, 1998 (Box 3)
  - APCC Workshop Master + Reprints, 1998 (Box 3)
  - Tooltime for Consultants: Both the Cutting Edge and the Basics ABC/APCC, 1998 (Box 3)
  - ABC/APCC Los Angeles 21st Century Consulting, 1999 (Box 3)
  - APCC/Middle Tennessee Chapter of ASTD Nashville, 1999-2000 (Box 3)
  - APCC/ABC Atlanta Reworking the Baseline, 1999-2000 (Box 3)
  - APCC Ready, Set, GROW Nashville, 2000-2001 (Box 3)
  - APCC Handouts, n.d. (Box 4)
  - Dan Dietrich materials, 1985-1992 (Box 4)
  - APCC Institutes, 2007-2011 (Box 4)
  - APCC Workshop Boston, 2004 (Box 4)
  - Across the Corporate Border: Organizational Development and Leadership, 2002 (Box 4)
  - ABC/APCC Workshop San Diego, 2001 (Box 4)
  - ABC/APCC Workshop Atlanta, 1998-2000 (Box 4)
  - Workshops, 2002-2011 (Box 4)
- Former APCC President Barbara Shwom Materials, 1981-2000
  - APWC Materials, 1988-2000 (Box 2)
  - Barbara Shwom Personal Correspondence, 1993-1994 (Box 2)
  - APWC Meetings, 1993 (Box 2)
  - APWC Reports, 1994 (Box 2)
  - APWC Board Meeting, 1992-1994 (Box 2)
  - Fee-setting Survey, 1992-1993 (Box 2)
  - APWC Tax Exemption Information, 1984-1992 (Box 2)
  - APWC in Print, 1981-1991 (Box 2)
  - Consulting Success Materials, 1990-1993 (Box 2)
  - APWC Policy Manual, 1987 (Box 2)
  - APWC Writings and Materials, 1992-1993 (Box 2)